Singing in her first movie musical!
Barbie as The Princess & the Pauper is a animation,
family, comedy film directed by William Lau.
In her first animated musical featuring seven original songs, Barbie comes to life in this modern
re-telling of a classic tale of mistaken identity and the power of friendship.
Based on the story by Mark Twain.
Princess Anneliese / Erika (voice), played by Kelly Sheridan.
Princess Anneliese (singing voice), played by Melissa Lyons.
Erika (singing voice), played by Julie Stevens.
King Dominick (voice), played by Mark Hildreth.
King Dominick (singing voice), played by Mark Luna.
Julian (voice), played by Alessandro Juliani.
Barbie as the Princess and the Pauper is a 2004 animated musical fantasy film.
It was released to video on September 28, 2004, and made its
television premiere on Nickelodeon on November 14, 2004.
This film is the first musical in the Barbie series.
It was directed by William Lau and stars the voice of Kelly Sheridan as
the Barbie protagonists, Princess Anneliese and Erika.
The plot is loosely inspired by the 1881 Mark Twain novel The Prince and the Pauper, and it is the first Barbie film that
completely excludes fantastic elements (fairies, magic, mermaids), which were a usual part of Barbie franchise.
It is generally regarded as one of the best films in the
franchise and has secured a strong cult following.
Songs for the film were composed by Amy Powers, Megan Cavallari and
Rob Hudnut, who also executive-produced the film.
The film was nominated for six DVD Exclusive Awards.
The film explores themes of princess, musical, based on
toy, female protagonist, identity swap.
The tone is lighthearted.